<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>munin on Espen Braastad</title>
    <link>/tags/munin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in munin on Espen Braastad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 23:32:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/munin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Temperature trend monitoring at home</title>
      <link>/posts/temperature-trend-monitoring-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 23:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/temperature-trend-monitoring-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Background I&amp;rsquo;ve got balanced ventilation in my apartment. It works OK, but I don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand how it behaves if knobs are pushed and pots are turned, and I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not sure if its performance is as good as I should expect.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to do some measurements to see how the system reacts to changes in the outside temperature and tuning of the various settings. The first parameter to measure is the temperature in the air intake, exhaust air and some of the ventilation valves in the different rooms in the apartment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>munincollector-ng</title>
      <link>/posts/munincollector-ng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 20:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/munincollector-ng/</guid>
      <description>Munincollector-ng is a perl script that collects graphs from multiple munin installations to display them in one page. A scenario where this is helpful is when you have (too) many munin clients on (too) many munin masters, and you want to look through some of the graphs - i.e. the Disk usage in percent (aka df) plugin - without spending/wasting too much time browsing through the less important graphs.
It consists of one perl script and one configuration file.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
