<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>netbooting on Espen Braastad</title>
    <link>/categories/netbooting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in netbooting on Espen Braastad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:20:20 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/netbooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ZFS NAS using CentOS 7 from tmpfs</title>
      <link>/posts/zfs-nas-on-tmpfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:20:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/zfs-nas-on-tmpfs/</guid>
      <description>Following up on the CentOS 7 root filesystem on tmpfs post, here comes a guide on how to run a ZFS enabled CentOS 7 NAS server (with the operating system) from tmpfs.
Hardware HP ProLiant MicroServer HP ProLiant MicroServer Remote Access Card AMD Turion(tm) II Neo N54L Dual-Core Processor 2x 8 GB 1333 MHZ ECC memory modules 4x 4 TB SATA hard drives (HGST, Western Digital and Seagate) Built-in Broadcom Limited NetXtreme BCM5723 Gigabit Ethernet adapter Preparing the build environment The disk image is built in macOS using Packer and VirtualBox.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 7 root filesystem on tmpfs</title>
      <link>/posts/centos-7-rootfs-on-tmpfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 21:34:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/centos-7-rootfs-on-tmpfs/</guid>
      <description>Several years ago I wrote a series of posts on how to run EL6 with its root filesystem on tmpfs. This post is a continuation of that series, and explains step by step how to run CentOS 7 with its root filesystem in memory. It should apply to RHEL, Ubuntu, Debian and other Linux distributions as well. The post is a bit terse to focus on the concept, and several of the steps have potential for improvements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CentOS/RHEL/SL 6: root filesystem on tmpfs, UPDATE #2</title>
      <link>/posts/el6-rootfs-on-tmpfs-update2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 21:44:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/el6-rootfs-on-tmpfs-update2/</guid>
      <description>Update 2017-06-30: Please see the updated guide which is more generic.
In a previous post, I’ve explained how to boot EL6 from memory without having / needing a physical disk.
A bright reader, Jeff, came up with an alternative method. This alternative method does not involve dd’ing the image into a loop device, but instead copying the contents of the disk image directly into tmpfs. The result is higher write/read performance and generally lower memory requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CentOS/RHEL/SL 6: root filesystem on tmpfs, UPDATE</title>
      <link>/posts/el6-rootfs-on-tmpfs-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 09:57:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/el6-rootfs-on-tmpfs-update/</guid>
      <description>Update 2017-06-30: Please see the updated guide which is more generic.
In EL6.4, the file /usr/share/dracut/modules.d/90dmsquash-live/dmsquash-live-root was updated so that the previous patch no longer works as it should. I’ve updated the patch, and here it is:
--- original 2013-03-20 16:25:23.698846581 +0100 +++ new 2013-03-21 08:58:11.175339694 +0100 @@ -24,6 +24,8 @@ getarg readonly_overlay &amp;amp;&amp;amp; readonly_overlay=&amp;#34;--readonly&amp;#34; || readonly_overlay=&amp;#34;&amp;#34; overlay=$(getarg overlay) +getarg toram &amp;amp;&amp;amp; toram=&amp;#34;yes&amp;#34; + # FIXME: we need to be able to hide the plymouth splash for the check really [ -e $livedev ] &amp;amp; fs=$(blkid -s TYPE -o value $livedev) if [ &amp;#34;$fs&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;iso9660&amp;#34; -o &amp;#34;$fs&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;udf&amp;#34; ]; then @@ -132,7 +134,10 @@ BASE_LOOPDEV=$( losetup -f ) losetup -r $BASE_LOOPDEV $EXT3FS - do_live_from_base_loop + # Create overlay only if toram is not set + if [ -z &amp;#34;$toram&amp;#34; ] ; then + do_live_from_base_loop + fi fi # we might have an embedded ext3 on squashfs to use as rootfs (compressed live) @@ -163,13 +168,66 @@ umount -l /squashfs - do_live_from_base_loop + # Create overlay only if toram is not set + if [ -z &amp;#34;$toram&amp;#34; ] ; then + do_live_from_base_loop + fi +fi + +# If the kernel parameter toram is set, create a tmpfs device and copy the +# filesystem to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CentOS/RHEL/SL 6: root filesystem on tmpfs</title>
      <link>/posts/el6-rootfs-on-tmpfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 21:44:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/el6-rootfs-on-tmpfs/</guid>
      <description>Update 2017-06-30: Please see the updated guide which is more generic.
UPDATE: The patch below has been updated here.
There are several scenarios where conventional hard drives are not really needed. Examples are HPC cluster nodes, virtualization nodes, home theater streaming PCs, silent desktops, internet cafés and embedded systems. Hard drives tend to fail, they are slow, they consume power, they generate heat and noise, and they are quite expensive if you need/want something faster and more reliable than SATA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KVM with iPXE in RHEL6</title>
      <link>/posts/kvm-with-ipxe-in-rhel6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 22:29:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kvm-with-ipxe-in-rhel6/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I discovered the amazing iPXE project. It is a complete PXE implementation with lots of nifty features, based on the gPXE project. Redhat ships the gPXE firmware for qemu and KVM, and you might want to use iPXE instead as the iPXE project currently seems to be more active. The major features (copied from ipxe.org):
boot from a web server via HTTP boot from an iSCSI SAN boot from a Fibre Channel SAN via FCoE boot from an AoE SAN boot from a wireless network boot from a wide-area network boot from an Infiniband network control the boot process with a script First, download the source code:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
