<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>filebin on Espen Braastad</title>
    <link>/categories/filebin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in filebin on Espen Braastad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 23:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/filebin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Filebin.net has moved to Hetzner</title>
      <link>/posts/filebin-moved-to-hetzner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 23:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/filebin-moved-to-hetzner/</guid>
      <description>About the move Yesterday, on the 20th of November 2023, the hosting of the filebin.net service was moved from Redpill Linpro in Norway to Hetzner in Germany. Shout out to Redpill Linpro for providing free hosting for 11 years!
Some history Filebin was a hobby project that let me learn the HTML5 File API. The end result made it easy to share photos and videos with friends and family, which was difficult at the time for non technical people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filebin upgrade</title>
      <link>/posts/filebin-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 20:40:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/filebin-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>https://filebin.net is a public and free file upload/sharing service. Its main design principle is to be incredibly simple to use.
It has been in production for several years, and has more or less been unmodified until now. Today it has been upgraded in several ways, and this post aims to elaborate on some of the changes.
Complete rewrite The previous version of Filebin was written in Python and kept meta data in MongoDB.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filebin available on http://filebin.net</title>
      <link>/posts/filebin-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 22:10:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/filebin-available/</guid>
      <description>Filebin.net was created to try out the new File API features in HTML5.
Filebin is a web application that is somewhat similar to a pastebin, except that it&amp;rsquo;s for files. It is written in Python, and the code is available on Github.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
